<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-04T19:27:26-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Silicon Economics Review</title><subtitle>Independent, data-driven economic reviews of the silicon industry — wafers, semiconductors, supply chains, and capital cycles.</subtitle><author><name>Silicon Economics Review</name><email></email></author><entry><title type="html">Foundry Capex Outlook</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/04/foundry-capex-outlook/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Foundry Capex Outlook" /><published>2025-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/04/foundry-capex-outlook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/04/foundry-capex-outlook/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Summary.</strong> Announced foundry capex points to a mixed picture: leading-edge logic nodes continue, while mature-node expansions moderate.</p>

<p><strong>Key watch items.</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>EUV tool shipments vs. install capacity</li>
  <li>Mature-node debottlenecking (power, water)</li>
  <li>Subsidy-driven projects and milestone timing</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Take.</strong> Expect staggered ramp timing; monitor tool vendors’ order books for confirmation.</p>]]></content><author><name>Editorial Team</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="foundry" /><category term="capex" /><category term="equipment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summary. Announced foundry capex points to a mixed picture: leading-edge logic nodes continue, while mature-node expansions moderate.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wafer Prices: Q3 Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/03/wafer-prices-q3-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wafer Prices: Q3 Review" /><published>2025-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/03/wafer-prices-q3-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/03/wafer-prices-q3-review/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Summary.</strong> The third quarter of 2025 witnessed a <strong>divergent pricing environment</strong> across wafer segments, with 300mm wafer pricing demonstrating remarkable stability while 200mm markets experienced meaningful tightening driven by specialty node demand. Contract pricing negotiations reflected <strong>stable utilization rates</strong> across leading global suppliers, with capacity constraints continuing to shape market dynamics.</p>

<p><strong>Context.</strong> The global wafer supply chain remains fundamentally constrained by <strong>extended lead times</strong> in crystal growth operations and polishing capacity limitations. Major suppliers including Shin-Etsu Chemical, SUMCO, and Siltronic continue to operate at <strong>near-maximum utilization rates</strong> of 95-98%, with new capacity additions limited by the 18-24 month lead times required for crystal pulling equipment installation. The industry’s <strong>consolidated supplier base</strong> has created structural supply discipline, with the top five suppliers controlling approximately <strong>85% of global 300mm capacity</strong> and <strong>78% of 200mm capacity</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Market Data and Pricing Analysis.</strong> The 300mm wafer segment, representing approximately <strong>70% of total wafer revenue</strong>, experienced minimal price movement with contracts showing <strong>flat to +1% quarter-over-quarter</strong> growth. This stability reflects the mature nature of high-volume 300mm production and the <strong>long-term contract structures</strong> that dominate relationships between leading foundries and wafer suppliers. Spot market activity remained limited, accounting for less than <strong>5% of total 300mm volume</strong>, with spot premiums averaging <strong>8-12% above contract pricing</strong>.</p>

<p>The 200mm segment demonstrated more pronounced pricing momentum with <strong>+2-4% quarter-over-quarter</strong> increases across most product categories. This tightening was particularly evident in automotive-grade and industrial-specification wafers, where demand growth of <strong>6-8% year-over-year</strong> has outpaced the industry’s modest capacity expansion. <strong>Reclaimed wafer pricing</strong> showed even stronger dynamics, with increases of <strong>4-6% quarter-over-quarter</strong> as supply remained constrained.</p>

<p>Specialty substrate markets, including <strong>Silicon Carbide (SiC) and Gallium Nitride (GaN)</strong>, exhibited significant pricing dispersion as the market continues to mature. SiC wafer pricing showed <strong>15-25% variance</strong> across suppliers, reflecting differences in crystal quality, defect density specifications, and supply chain reliability. The <strong>150mm SiC market</strong> experienced particular tightness, with lead times extending to <strong>20-26 weeks</strong> for automotive-qualified substrates.</p>

<p><strong>Outlook.</strong> Base case: modest ASP expansion through next quarter as utilization normalizes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Editorial Team</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="wafers" /><category term="pricing" /><category term="capacity" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summary. The third quarter of 2025 witnessed a divergent pricing environment across wafer segments, with 300mm wafer pricing demonstrating remarkable stability while 200mm markets experienced meaningful tightening driven by specialty node demand. Contract pricing negotiations reflected stable utilization rates across leading global suppliers, with capacity constraints continuing to shape market dynamics.]]></summary></entry></feed>