<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-04T19:28:37-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Silicon Economics Review</title><subtitle>Independent, data-driven economic reviews of the silicon industry — wafers, semiconductors, supply chains, and capital cycles.</subtitle><author><name>Silicon Economics Review</name><email></email></author><entry><title type="html">Foundry Capex Outlook</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/04/foundry-capex-outlook/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Foundry Capex Outlook" /><published>2025-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/04/foundry-capex-outlook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/04/foundry-capex-outlook/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Summary.</strong> Announced foundry capex points to a mixed picture across the semiconductor manufacturing landscape. Leading-edge logic nodes at <strong>3nm and below</strong> continue to attract substantial investment, with TSMC allocating approximately <strong>$32-36 billion</strong> in capital expenditure for 2025, while Samsung maintains a <strong>$25-28 billion</strong> commitment. However, mature-node expansions are showing signs of moderation as demand patterns shift and capacity utilization rates stabilize around <strong>85-90%</strong> for nodes above 28nm.</p>

<p>The current foundry investment cycle reflects a fundamental divergence between cutting-edge process technology development and established manufacturing capabilities. <strong>TSMC’s Arizona facilities</strong> represent a <strong>$40 billion</strong> commitment through 2026, focusing on 4nm and 3nm production with initial capacity targets of <strong>20,000 wafers per month</strong> by late 2024. Meanwhile, Intel’s foundry services division has earmarked <strong>$20 billion</strong> for Ohio fabrication facilities, targeting <strong>18A and 20A nodes</strong> with production readiness expected by 2025.</p>

<p><strong>Key watch items</strong> include EUV tool shipments versus actual install capacity, where ASML’s delivery schedule indicates <strong>55-60 High-NA EUV systems</strong> planned for 2025 across all customers. Current installation capacity suggests potential bottlenecks, as each High-NA system requires <strong>6-8 months</strong> for complete setup and qualification. The mature-node segment faces infrastructure constraints, particularly regarding <strong>power distribution and water cooling systems</strong>. Facilities operating at nodes between <strong>40nm and 180nm</strong> are experiencing debottlenecking challenges, with power requirements increasing <strong>15-20%</strong> annually due to higher throughput demands.</p>

<p>Subsidy-driven projects across multiple regions are creating additional complexity in timing predictions. The <strong>CHIPS Act allocation</strong> of <strong>$52.7 billion</strong> has triggered numerous domestic expansion announcements, though actual disbursement schedules remain tied to specific milestone achievements. European initiatives under the <strong>EU Chips Act</strong> targeting <strong>43 billion euros</strong> in combined public and private investment are similarly structured around performance-based releases.</p>

<p><strong>GlobalFoundries</strong> has committed <strong>$3.1 billion</strong> primarily for mature-node capacity expansion in Malta and Singapore, focusing on automotive and IoT applications where demand visibility extends through 2027. UMC’s capital allocation of <strong>$1.8 billion</strong> emphasizes specialty processes including <strong>BCD and RFSOI technologies</strong>, responding to power management and RF connectivity requirements.</p>

<p>The equipment vendor landscape provides additional insight into foundry investment patterns. <strong>Applied Materials</strong> reported foundry-related orders representing <strong>65%</strong> of total semiconductor equipment bookings in Q3 2024, while <strong>Lam Research</strong> indicated <strong>40%</strong> growth in foundry segment revenues year-over-year. These figures suggest sustained momentum despite broader industry cyclicality.</p>

<p><strong>Take.</strong> Expect staggered ramp timing across different technology nodes and geographical regions through 2026. Leading-edge facilities will likely achieve meaningful production volumes by <strong>Q3 2025</strong>, while mature-node expansions face longer lead times due to infrastructure limitations. Monitor tool vendors’ order books quarterly for confirmation of sustained momentum, particularly <strong>ASML’s EUV delivery schedules</strong> and <strong>KLA’s process control equipment</strong> orders, which serve as leading indicators for actual fab readiness. The <strong>18-24 month lag</strong> between equipment orders and production ramp remains a critical factor in capacity planning accuracy.</p>]]></content><author><name>Editorial Team</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="foundry" /><category term="capex" /><category term="equipment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summary. Announced foundry capex points to a mixed picture across the semiconductor manufacturing landscape. Leading-edge logic nodes at 3nm and below continue to attract substantial investment, with TSMC allocating approximately $32-36 billion in capital expenditure for 2025, while Samsung maintains a $25-28 billion commitment. However, mature-node expansions are showing signs of moderation as demand patterns shift and capacity utilization rates stabilize around 85-90% for nodes above 28nm.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wafer Prices: Q3 Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/03/wafer-prices-q3-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wafer Prices: Q3 Review" /><published>2025-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/03/wafer-prices-q3-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/03/wafer-prices-q3-review/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Summary.</strong> The third quarter of 2025 witnessed a <strong>divergent pricing environment</strong> across wafer segments, with 300mm wafer pricing demonstrating remarkable stability while 200mm markets experienced meaningful tightening driven by specialty node demand. Contract pricing negotiations reflected <strong>stable utilization rates</strong> across leading global suppliers, with capacity constraints continuing to shape market dynamics.</p>

<p><strong>Context.</strong> The global wafer supply chain remains fundamentally constrained by <strong>extended lead times</strong> in crystal growth operations and polishing capacity limitations. Major suppliers including Shin-Etsu Chemical, SUMCO, and Siltronic continue to operate at <strong>near-maximum utilization rates</strong> of 95-98%, with new capacity additions limited by the 18-24 month lead times required for crystal pulling equipment installation. The industry’s <strong>consolidated supplier base</strong> has created structural supply discipline, with the top five suppliers controlling approximately <strong>85% of global 300mm capacity</strong> and <strong>78% of 200mm capacity</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Market Data and Pricing Analysis.</strong> The 300mm wafer segment, representing approximately <strong>70% of total wafer revenue</strong>, experienced minimal price movement with contracts showing <strong>flat to +1% quarter-over-quarter</strong> growth. This stability reflects the mature nature of high-volume 300mm production and the <strong>long-term contract structures</strong> that dominate relationships between leading foundries and wafer suppliers. Spot market activity remained limited, accounting for less than <strong>5% of total 300mm volume</strong>, with spot premiums averaging <strong>8-12% above contract pricing</strong>.</p>

<p>The 200mm segment demonstrated more pronounced pricing momentum with <strong>+2-4% quarter-over-quarter</strong> increases across most product categories. This tightening was particularly evident in automotive-grade and industrial-specification wafers, where demand growth of <strong>6-8% year-over-year</strong> has outpaced the industry’s modest capacity expansion. <strong>Reclaimed wafer pricing</strong> showed even stronger dynamics, with increases of <strong>4-6% quarter-over-quarter</strong> as supply remained constrained.</p>

<p>Specialty substrate markets, including <strong>Silicon Carbide (SiC) and Gallium Nitride (GaN)</strong>, exhibited significant pricing dispersion as the market continues to mature. SiC wafer pricing showed <strong>15-25% variance</strong> across suppliers, reflecting differences in crystal quality, defect density specifications, and supply chain reliability. The <strong>150mm SiC market</strong> experienced particular tightness, with lead times extending to <strong>20-26 weeks</strong> for automotive-qualified substrates.</p>

<p><strong>Outlook.</strong> Base case: modest ASP expansion through next quarter as utilization normalizes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Editorial Team</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="wafers" /><category term="pricing" /><category term="capacity" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summary. The third quarter of 2025 witnessed a divergent pricing environment across wafer segments, with 300mm wafer pricing demonstrating remarkable stability while 200mm markets experienced meaningful tightening driven by specialty node demand. Contract pricing negotiations reflected stable utilization rates across leading global suppliers, with capacity constraints continuing to shape market dynamics.]]></summary></entry></feed>